Guide to the Valerie Taylor papers, 1913-1997
Taylor, Valerie papers, 1913-1997
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - c. General Correspondence
      - Dewey, Janice, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Dawn, Angela, June 27, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Devore, George, June 23-July 21, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Dove, Victor, (Feb.)- Jan. 30, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Dreamdigger, Ruth (Ruth Travis-Best), n.d., Mar. 10, 1985-(June) 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Eastman, Wes, (Sept.)- Oct. 28, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Fawcett, Eugenia, and Mary Milner, (July?) 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Finke, Nancy, and David, n.d., Feb. 16, 1981-Dec. 26, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Aug. 26, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Fleishman, Enid, Jan. 27, 1992-Sept. 30, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Fleishman, Jane, Dec. 17, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Gerber/Hart Gay and Lesbian Library & Archives, (Oct.?) 1994, July 24, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Gershick, Zsa Zsa, July 21, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Gidlow, Elsa, Jan. 4-Nov. 17, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Greenham Women Against Cruise Missiles, June 15, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Hall, Lillian, Mar. 11, 1986-Oct. 14, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Hall, Robert, (May) 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Hyatt, Arthur. Includes note by James Tate, (February?) 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Hobson, Arline, Dec. 31, 1984-Sept. 3, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Howland, Terry, n.d., Feb. 21, 1989-Sept. 23, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Hyatt, Arthur, n.d., ca. February 1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Inman, Will. Includes photocopy of letter from Meridel Le Sueur to Inman, May 23, 1981-Aug. 31, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Jackson, Nicola (Saphira), May 3, 1988, June 28, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Janet, Feb. 19, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Joanna and Andrea (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Johnson, Hansje, Mar. 28, 1995-June 23, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Kelly, Bill, December 1994 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Klosinski, Denise, n.d., April 1984-March 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Kuda, Marie. See also: "Womanpress" in Business Correspondence, Nov. 18, 1993-July 31, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Lane, Linn, Aug. 30, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Lenoir, Lora, May 29, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Lesbian Herstory Archives, April 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Le Sueur, Meridel. See also: "West End Press" in Business Correspondence, November 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Lochman, Edna and Doug, n.d., Sept. 21, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Lynch, Lee, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Lynch, Lee, (Cont'd), Apr. 24, 1981-April 1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Marchant, Anyda, Apr. 8, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Mariah, Paul, Mar. 19-Sept. 6, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Mary and Jim, Jan. 4, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Mead, Edward (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Letter of June 14, 1981 includes tape. See: Series X. Audio and Video Tapes. (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Mayer, Ada and Hank. Includes several photographs of the Mayers and their sons, n.d., Aug. 1979-May 12, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Mayer, Noni and Corey, n.d., Feb. 18-May 25, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - McCarthy, Florence, n.d., Feb. 25, 1980-Nov. 18, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Mead, Ed (Includes four transcripts of seven tapes sent by Mead's wife, Carey Catherine, from Nicaragua. See Series X. Audio and Video Tapes. See also: "Catherine, Carey" in General Correspondence., Feb. 9, 1981-July 21, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Meader, Norm and Richard Holmes, Dec. 21, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Michele, Sept. 30, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Michigan, University of, Ann Arbor. Women's Studies Department (Ellen Zweig), Oct. 29, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Morton, Don, n.d., Nov. 27, 1979-Oct. 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Murphy, Lynn, n.d., Jan. 19, 1980-Aug. 12, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Murphy, Sheila, Apr. 3, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Naylor, Lucinda, Dec. 16, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Osborn, Torie, July, December 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Overman, Caroline, December 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Owens, Vicki, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Parrish, Kathryn Taylor, May 26, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Pattee, Christine, Oct. 14 and Nov. 9, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Pease, Randal (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Penny, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Pima County Health Department (Arizona), Nov. 17, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Pima Friends Meeting (Arizona), Mar. 26, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Polly and Nancy (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Pope, Penelope and Stephanie Lee, Jan. 9 and Mar. 14, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Ray, Judy and David, Oct. 21, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Reagan, Betsy, Sept. 14, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Routsong, Alma (Isabel Miller), Mar. 29, 1977-Apr. 6, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Ruby, Sept. 2 and 14, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Rule, Jane, Apr. 7, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - S. Bob, June 10, 1990-May 25, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Samaras, Constance, Dec. 1979 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Sara, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Sarton, May, Dec. 1, 1977-[Sept. or Oct.] 1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Scott, Stephanie Lee, [December 1983] (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Sharon, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Sirius, Jean, n.d., Mar. 4, 1980-May 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Stevens, Linda, n.d., June 1991-Aug. 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Stevenson, Janet, Nov. 21, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Stevis, Dimitris, Jan. 6, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Steinecker, David L., Oct. 28, 1988-Dec. 1995 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Stina, Inga, Nov. 1, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Swanson, Diane, n.d., Jan. 31, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Terkel, Studs, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Tucson, Arizona. Sun Station Post Office, Feb. 22, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Uszkurat, Carol Ann, Jan. 1, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Van Dyckle, Bernardene, Feb. 20, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Wagner, Mary Carol and Jorge-Romero Ortez, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Weiner, Tess, Sept. 24, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Weldy, Ann, Mar. 22, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Wini, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Women's Resource Center, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Woman Kraft, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Yo and Bonnie (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Walters, Helen. On audio tape. Includes note by James Tate. See Series X. Audio and Video Tapes. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Fan Mail (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Business, Oct. 26, 1975-Aug. 14, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - General (Primarily to Jean Sirius and Cara Vaughn), June 10, 1976-July 7, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Series III. Literary Manuscripts
  - Published Works
    - Book-length works
      - The Growing Time. Published as Ripening, original draft, t.s., pp. 1-180, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - The Growing Time. Published as Ripening, carbon, t.s., 180pp., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - The Prism, ts., carbon, 174pp.+parts of older draft, 66pp., n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Rice and Beans. Marked: first draft. Includes comments by James Tate, t.s., 1-67pp. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Rice and Beans. Marked: "final draft," ts., 104pp. (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Rice and Beans, (Cont'd), pp. 105-173 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Rice and Beans (wrong title?) first draft; incomplete, t.s., 62pp. (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Ripening, draft, ts., 120pp., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Ripening, draft, ts., pp. 121-183, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Various book fragments, including Whisper Their Love, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Published Short Stories
      - "My Father's Chilblains" (by Velma Young Tate). In: The Catholic Home Journal, November 1950, p. 6. (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - "The Home Place" (by Nacella Young). In: The Canadian Forum, November 1951, pp. 177-8. (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - "A Different Kind of Love", ts., carbon, 7pp. In: True Story [?], Aug. 8, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - I Married a Brain-Damaged Alcoholic (by Velma Tate). In: True Love [?], ts., carbon, 11pp., Aug. 9, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - My Home Was a Nightmare, ts., 9pp.; carbon, ts., 9pp. Includes note from MacFadden Women's Group. In: True confessions [?], Aug. 9, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Published Poems
      - By Nacella Young; clippings from journals and magazines, Jan. 1947-Dec. 1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - By Nacella Young, ts., 15pp., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - By Valerie Taylor, in: Newsletter Inago, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Published Articles and Essays
      - Clippings from journals and magazines; include notes by James Tate, late 1950-November 1950 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Essays on Denise Levertov and May Sarton for Feminist Writers. Includes correspondence, ts. drafts, and a note by James Tate. See also: " Feminist Writers" in Business Correspondence., 1995/1996 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Unpublished works
    - Book-length works
      - Untitled; "Barbara Hanson was up on a ladder..." by "Taylor" ts., 139pp., n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Untitled; "Coal bill. The words echoed..." by "Tate"; ts., 182pp., n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Untitled; "Elizabeth Davis..." Includes early drafts and James Tate's notes, ts., 180pp. (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Portion of unidentified novel: "Fifteen minutes before closing time..." ts., 6pp., n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - The Chicken of the Hotel Oracio Nelson by "Velma N. Tate," ts., carbon, 153pp., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - The Different Ones, revision, ts., carbon, 180pp., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Dry September; Chapter Two, by "Nacella Young," ts., 14pp.; ts., carbon by "Velma Tate," 183pp., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Every Day Is Monday, by "Velma Tate," t.s., with corrections, 133pp. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Hand Off My Love, ts., photocopy of carbon, 67pp. (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - The Home Place, source material, t.s., ca. 120pp., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - The Home Place, draft, t.s., 150pp., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - The Home Place (Cont'd), t.s., pp. 151-311, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - The Home Place, "rewrite," t.s., 118pp., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - The Home Place, by "Velma Tate," t.s., carbon, 150pp., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - The Home Place, (Cont'd), t.s., carbon, pp. 151-296, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - The Home Place, by "Valerie Taylor," final version, t.s., 179pp., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - The Home Place (Cont'd), pp. 180-385, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - The Housekeeper's Daughter, by "Francine Davenport," ts., carbon, 193pp., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Innocent Imposter, by "Francine Davenport," ts., carbon, 134pp., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - The Innocent Imposters, by "Francine Davenport,"includes alternate ending on carbon, 151pp. (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Island of Love, by "Francine Davenport," ts., 69pp. (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Island of Love, by "Francine Davenport," ts., carbon, 69pp. (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Love Image, ts., carbon, 156pp., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - More Than Bed, ts., 148, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - 1933, ts., 101pp., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - 1933, ts., pp. 102-184, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - 1924, early draft, ts., pp. 1-5, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - 1924, incomplete copy, ts., pp. 2-10, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - 1924, photocopy of complete version, ts., 5pp., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Object Matrimony. Iincludes comments by James Tate, ts., with corrections, 138pp., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Object Matrimony, (Cont'd), pp. 139-201, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Object Matrimony, duplicate, with name "Tate" crossed out and corrected to "Taylor," ts., 201pp. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Sequel to Jam [?], ts., 87pp., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Seven Lean Years, draft, with corrections ts., 252pp., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Seven Lean Years, draft, corrected. Includes James Tate's comments, ts., 143pp., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Seven Lean Years, (Cont'd), pp. 144-268, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Sight Unseen, draft, ts., several paginations, ca. 160pp. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - The Small Rain, ts., carbon, 165pp., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Stand By and Witness, ts., incomplete and corrected pagination, with corrections in pen, 151pp. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Stand By and Witness, ts., carbon, 151pp. Includes alternative ending (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - The Tormented Search, ts., carbon, 140pp., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Waiting to Die, ts., 24pp., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Unpublished Short Stories
      - Birthday, ts., photocopy, 8pp., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Christmas Eve in Adelaide, by Velma Tate, ts., carbon, 10pp., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Cora, by Velma Tate, ts., 8pp.; carbon, ts., 7pp., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Resurrection, by "Nacella Young," ts., 7pp., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - A Dream, ts., 1p., May 1984 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - A Short Love Story, ts., 2pp., 1993 or 1994 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Nine short stories, untitled, with notes by Valerie Taylor and James Tate; 1997[?]; ts., 2pp.; 3pp.; 5pp.; 5pp.; 5pp.; 9pp.; 7pp.; 5pp.; 4pp., respectively (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Unpublished Poems
      - Loose poems
        - Loose poems. Includes an essay on Tee Corinne and note by James Tate ts., 5pp. (Box 23, Folder 1)
        - Loose poems (Cont'd), Include note by James Tate ts., 3pp., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 2)
        - Loose poems (Cont'd), "The Rooted Heart" and other poems, with explanatory note by James Tate, 1952? (Box 23, Folder 3)
        - Loose poems (Cont'd), "After the Apalachian trail: a dialogue for Roberta," ts., 2pp., ca. 1995 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Poems from Valerie Taylor's journals
        - First grouping from binder in its original state, not in any particular order ts., ca. 100pp., ca. 1945-1961 (Box 23, Folder 5)
        - Second grouping from binder, some published[?], ts., ca. 60pp., 1945-1985 (Box 23, Folder 6)
        - Third grouping from binder, some published[?], ts., ca. 150pp., few dates, ca. 1946-1950 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Photocopies of poems
        - Photocopies of poems. With note by Tee Corinne, ts., ca. 30pp, 1980s? (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Translation of poetry
        - "Translations from the German," ts., ca. 100pp., n.d. (Box 24, Folder 2)
        - Translations [?] ts., ca. 30pp., n.d. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished Articles and Essays, n.d., 1977-1988?
      - Biographical sketch of Pearl M. Hart, with note by James Tate, n.d. ms. and ts. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "B.J. was a seeker..." n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "The Cosmic Girl" n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "Did you know?..." Fragment of essays [?], n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "Have you ever wondered what happened to old amazons?..." n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "In one of Chicago's older cemeteries..." n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "Jeannette Foster, Forerunner" n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "Since time immemorial..." ts., 1p. n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "The time has come to redefine peace..." n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "What Has Happened to the Fat Ladies?" n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "The World Is Ours: A Statement Against Separatism" n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "In life, paths meet..." fragment of article [?], 1977? (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "Habitat for Humanity," 1987 [?] (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "The Crack in the Closet Door," 1988 [?] (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Series IV. Interviews, Lectures, and Speeches
  - unidentified event/circumstances Valerie Taylor on audio cassette tape. See: Series X. Audio and Video Tapes.
  - Interviews, n.d., 1983-1991
    - Arizona Gay TV show: # 10, "Growing old and gay--an interview with Valerie Taylor." Also includes "Best of Arizona Gay." Video tape. See: Series X. Audio and Video Tapes. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - "Beware the Dream That Comes True Out of Season" conducted by Kathryn Taylor Parrish, student paper, ts., photocopy, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - "Valerie Taylor, writer" excerpts of interview conducted by Linn Lane, published in: Magazine, November 1983, p. 9. Whole issue. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - "Valerie Taylor" in The San Francisco Bay Area Gay & Lesbian Historical Society Newsletter, no. 4, v. 4 Summer 1989, pp. 1, 4. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - "Valerie Taylor Interview" conducted by Tee Corinne and Caroline Overman, published in Common Lives/Lesbian Lives, no. 25 Winter 1988 and in: Valerie Taylor Author: A Resource Book, by Tee Corinne, 1991. Photocopy of ts., 15pp. See also: Personal Records (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - "I Like My Characters" ts., pp. 45-54, conducted on Mar. 30, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Lectures
    - Transcripts of eight lectures: "Our Lesbian Roots" delivered at Casa Nuestra in Tucson, AZ, in January and February 1980 Lectures one-four. See Also: Series X. Audio and Video Tapes. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - "Our Lesbian Roots" (Cont'd), Lectures five-eight., 1980 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, n.d., 1974-1978
    - Untitled; on wars in history; ms. n.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Untitled; on women in Valerie Taylor's family, ms. n.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Untitled "America's senior citizens..." n.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - "Jane Addams," n.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Untitled "The Korean War..." n.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - "For My Granddaughters..." delivered before the 1st Annual Lesbian Writers Conference in Chicago September 13, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - "May Sarton: A Study in Growth," delivered at the Fourth Annual Lesbian Writers' Conference in Chicago, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - "Will Shakespeare's Sister," delivered Nov. 4, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - "We're Not There Yet," delivered at the Gay and Lesbian Pride Week, Chicago, June 23, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Various events
    - Phil Donahue show, with Valerie Taylor, Del Martin, Fred Monroe, and Joe Norton. Video tape. See Also: Series X. Audio and Video Tapes., 1982 or 1983 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Poetry workshop at Flower Square retirement home. Three audio cassette tapes. See Series X. Audio and Video Tapes., 1984 or 1985 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Series V. Literary, Social and Political Activities
  - Human rights/social justice, ca. 1980s (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Gay and Lesbian, ca. 1970s and 1980s (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Literary, ca. 1970s to 1990s (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Peace, ca. 1980s and 1990s (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Quakers, ca. 1980s and 1990s (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Series VI. Public Reception
  - Awards
    - Chicago Gay and Lesbian Hall of Fame. November 1992. Includes Valerie Taylor among 1992 inductees (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Books Reviews
    - Books Reviews, n.d., Fall 1981-July/August 1991 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Book Reviews (Cont'd), collected by Naiad Press, May 1982-Sept/Oct. 1992 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - News stories
    - News stories, n.d., Sept. 18, 1960-Spring 1998 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Publishers' book catalogs
    - Publishers' book catalogs, ca. 1982-1989 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Ads and announcements
    - Ads and announcements of Valerie Taylor's books or lectures (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Other materials, 1985-1990
    - Blurb on Valerie Taylor in The Gay Engagement Calendar, 1985, on September 7th. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Photograph of Valerie Taylor with Del Martin 1984 in: Out/Look, Summer 1988, p. 37. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Valerie Taylor's photo and bibliography in Lesbian Muse, 1990, including a dedication and a letter from Tee Corinne (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - News stories and reviews about Valerie Taylor (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Series VII. Writings by and About Others
  - Unpublished and published poems by Jeannette Foster. Includes note by Tee Corinne (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - "Author's preface" by Tee Corinne, 3pp + photographs, photocopy., n.d. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Hank [Clarence H.] Mayers' autobiography, typed from tape. Includes note by Tee Corinne; two runs [?] ts., ca. 250pp., n.d. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - "The Good Fight," by Hank [Clarence H.] Mayers, ts., 150pp., carbons, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Works by Will Inman, mostly poetry, ts., photocopies, and some clippings, ca. 150pp., 1980s (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
  - Works by Will Inman (Cont'd), ca. 150pp., 1980s (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
  - Works by Will Inman (Cont'd), booklets and broadsides, 1977-1989 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Clippings on Will Inman, 1967-1985 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Short stories by Vera J. Terrell, ts., ca. 20pp, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Poetry by Frank Shutts, ts., ca. 100Pp. Includes note by Tee Corinne, mostly early 1990s (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Various authors, ts., with notes by James Tate, ts., ca. 50pp, various dates (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified writings, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Works about others--Includes notes by James Tate and Tee Corinne, various dates (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Materials sent by Marie Kuda. Include a letter from Kuda to Valerie Taylor, Oct. 17, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- Series VIII. Photographs
  - Valerie Taylor's early photographs, 1920-1940
    - Her first schoolhouse [?], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Large portrait, ca. 1917 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - With mother, sister, and grandparents, two photographs, ca. 1920 and 1927 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Small prints with other schoolchildren (Valerie Taylor in three of them) ca. 1920 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Small portraits, two photographs, 1920 and ca. 1930 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - On wagon at farm, with mother and sister [?], ca. 1935 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - With sister Rose Marie, five photographs, ca. 1920 and 1930s (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - At Blackburn College, ca. 1935 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - With family, five photographs, ca. 1930s (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - With son Marshall, ca. 1940 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook, 1930s-1940. Includes several notes by James Tate (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - At Blackburn College, large portrait, 1937 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - With husband William Jerry Tate, newlyweds [?], two photographs, ca. 1939 or 1940 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Valerie Taylor from the 1950s to the 1990s, 1950-1997
    - With glasses, two photographs, ca. 1950s (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - With sons Marshall, Jim, and Jerry, husband Jerry, and step-mother Jerri, three photographs, Christmas morning 1956 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - In Chicago, four prints, ca. 1959. Photo by Al Vaughn. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - With Marvin De Koren, ca. 1960s (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - In Chicago, ca. 1960s (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - With Ada Mayer, August 9, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - With Lola Sherlock and Marvi De Koven, Chicago, five photographs, ca. late 1960s. Includes notes by James Tate (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - With Marshall John Tate, Ada Mayer, and Hank Mayer (includes note by James Tate), ca. 1970s (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - At home, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - With Ada Mayer, October 1971 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - With grand-daughter Suzie, with son Marshall, and with daughter-in-law Hye Sook, in front of house where Taylor lived in Margaretville, NY, five photographs, between 1975 and 1978 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - With Penni Tate, ca. late 1970s (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Portrait, late 1970s (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Large portraits, by herslef and with friend. Two photographs by Bill Girden, ca. late 1970s (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - With Tee Corinne in Margaretville, NY. Contact sheet and three prints, late 1970s (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Holding a friend's baby, ca. 1980s [?] (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - At Grant Street, with unidentified friend and by herself, two photographs, early 1980s (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - At Grant Street with her lady dog, two photographs, early 1980s (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - With Will Inman in tucson, AZ, two photographs, ca. 1982 (Box 33, Folder 19)